Ajay Govind S

Designer | Developer | Tester

+(971) 50288 9693 - +(91) 9488 949470 - <u>ajaygovin@gmail.com</u> <u>https://ajaygovinds.github.io/</u>

TOTAL

3 years
8 months

ABOUT ME

An ardent Design Thinker and I love aesthetics.

Basically I'm a Philomath and have a 3+ years of blended hands-on industrial experience in Graphical Designing, Ux/Ui Designing, Media Printing, Web Development, Android App 2D 3D Development, Animation, OOPS and SDLC technologies, and Selenium Automation Testing using Java.

My principle is to work for the people or organizations who value the job as an advanced tool for helping and learning for themselves and others. I look forward to work in that kind of system.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Tester – Ux Ui

Etisalat Telecommunications, Dubai - (Sep. 2019 - Aug. 2021)

- Preached design thinking strategy by helping the UAT team in verifying and validating the User Interface (UI) the User Experience (UX) for every in-house B2C digital products.
- Sharing knowledge opened opportunites to work with Etisalat's web, mobile (Android & iOS) and SAS (Selft Assisted Service) applications.
- I proactively acted by developing a Google Chrome Extension that automatically extract testers' execution effort and generate the DSR (Daily Status Report) by opening the mail application for them.

Graphical & Ux Ui Designer

Knowledge Lens, Bangalore, India – (Oct. 2018 – Aug. 2019)

- I had designed inventory management dashboard, in-house learning module dashboard, PCB's (Pollution Control Board) dashboard for few states in India which displays the monitored AQI (Air Quality Index) values from their cities.
- I made sure that all stakeholders were on the same page while designing mockups or prototypes by working closely with developers, project managers, technical leads and sometimes with the CEO too.
- I helped the content management team by designing LinkedIn & Facebook posters, Infographics and used to design icons that will be shared with the developers for implementation.

EXPERIENCE (contd...)

Programmer Analyst Trainee

Cognizant Technology Solutions, India – (Dec. 2017 – Sep. 2018)

- I was trained in Automation Testing using Selenium and Core Java along with MySQL.
- My knowledge on CITS (Cognizant Intelligent Test Scripter) and TestNG helped the team to integrate them in the SDLC process to expedite the deliverables at the proper timeline.
- My responsibilities also included in creating End-to-End test scripts, Regression suits, and scripts for Unit Testing using Mayen.

EDUCATION

ODL, 2021 - Present

M. B. A.

Amrita Vishwa Vidhyapeetham University, India

ODL, 2020 - Present

M. Sc. Applied Psychology

Annamalai University, India

Full-time, 2013 - 2017

B. Tech. Computer Science Eng.

Amrita Vishwa Vidhyapeetham University, India

Full-time, 2000 - 2012

K12 – MPC | Computer Science

Amrita Vidyalayam, India

SKILLS

{ < Coding > }

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, JSON, Java, Wordpresss, PHP, MySQL, Selenium (used for automation), TestNG, Python, C/C++, ReactJS

IDEs' & Editors

Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, Intellij IDEA, Atom, Eclipse, Adobe Dreamweaver

2D & 3D Tools

Blender, Unity, Adobe Animate (previously called as Flash)

Designing & Editing Tools

Adobe Illustrator, Gravit Designer, Inkscape, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Acrobat

Wireframing & Prototyping Tools

Pen & Paper, Adobe XD, Invision Studio, Balsamiq, Figma, UXPin

Other Technologies

Buildbox (game design & development tool), Github, cPanel, MS Word, MS Excel, MS Powerpoint, Notepad++, Linux (basic), Libre Office, Arduino (basic), CLI (basics in Linux & Windows), Basics of Computer Networking

What else?

- Adhering to the principles of Design Thinking process before anything.
- Designing & developing web application with CRUD operations.
- Managing hosted files using cPanel.
- Version-control using Git.
- Designing & developing Android application.
- Host & manage Wordpress websites.
- Developing Google Chrome Extension with database integration.
- Vector drawing but not limited to designing Infographics, Business cards, Flyers, Posters, Letter pad, Logo, Social media posts.
- Designing & developing automation scripts for web automation & for monotonous tasks.
- Creating 2D & 3D animations.